<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hello on Scrivener</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Hello on Scrivener</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Four ways to make an API call in JS</title><link>/techdoc/api/4waysapi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/api/4waysapi/</guid><description>There are many ways to make an API call in different programming languages. In JavaScript an API could be called in four ways:
XMLHttpRequest Fetch API Axios JQuery Use JSON Placeholder service to get API data. It has an endpoint with 10 users data.
How to present API data in a table If you need to present API in the table, create an index.html file with the code showed below.</description></item><item><title>Function.prototype.bind()</title><link>/techdoc/javascript/bind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/javascript/bind/</guid><description>The bind() method creates a new function that, when called, has its this keyword set to the provided value, with a given sequence of arguments preceding any provided when the new function is called.
const person1 = { name: &amp;#39;Oleh&amp;#39;, age: 46, logInfo: function() { console.log(`Name is ${this.name}`); console.log(`Age is ${this.age}`); } }; const person2 = { name: &amp;#34;Svitlana&amp;#34;, age: 37 }; person1.logInfo(); person1.logInfo.bind(person2)(); As a result of using the method bind(), it is possible to borrow the logInfo function of person1 object to the person2 object.</description></item><item><title>How to make commits locally and globally</title><link>/techdoc/git/commit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/git/commit/</guid><description>After you created new repository with {git init} or cloned an existing repository with {git clone {repository address}}, open your terminal in the local repository folder with the command:
cd {name of repository folder} After you made some changes in your local repository folder you need to index them with {git add} command:
git add . -&amp;gt; add the {space + dot} after {add} to index all the changed files.</description></item><item><title>Quality of Service in MQTT Integration Setup</title><link>/techdoc/mqtt/qos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/mqtt/qos/</guid><description>You can select an MQTT Quality of Service (QoS) level during the Integration Setup procedure. We use MQTT QoS level 0 (At most once) by default.
ThingsBoard supports MQTT QoS level 1, which means that a client receives a response to the publish message only after data is stored to Cassandra DB. Data duplicates which are possible with QoS level 1 are just the overwrites to the corresponding Cassandra row and thus are not present in persisted data.</description></item><item><title>Наталі Гендел: «Бути політичним означає бути залученим»</title><link>/articles/litakcent/handal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/litakcent/handal/</guid><description>Інтервʼю Поетка Наталі Гендел мешкає в Нью-Йорку – космополітичному котлі світу, де змішалися всі нації та народності, але вона весь час пам’ятає про своє палестинське коріння. Гендел пише для Vanity Fair, Guernica Magazine, The Guardian, The New York Times, The Nation, Virginia Quarterly Review, Ploughshares, її п’єси йдуть у Центрі Джона Кенеді та Вестмінстерському Аббатстві. Антологія арабських поеток під її редакцією увійшла до списку 10 кращих книжок феміністичної літератури за версією The Guardian.</description></item><item><title>Callback Function</title><link>/techdoc/javascript/callback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/javascript/callback/</guid><description>The Callback function creates a function inside the other function as a parameter. As it is showed in the example below, checkInput function has a cb callback function as a first parameter and &amp;hellip;strings variable as a second rest parameter. The callback function is called only when hasEmptyText condition is false, that means that there is no empty strings in the &amp;hellip;strings variable. When checkInput function is called there is an array function ()=&amp;gt; as a cb callback function in its parameters and several strings in the &amp;hellip;strings variable.</description></item><item><title>Create an invite to sign for a merged document group</title><link>/techdoc/api/createinvite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/api/createinvite/</guid><description>POST Copy https://api-eval.signnow.com/documentgroup/{{group_id}}/groupinvite Creates an invite to sign for a merged document group. group_id TBD. (ask developers about group id data type and how to find it)
Requirements (if any):
TBD. It is necessary to specify special requirements from the developers of the API. Request Headers Authorization string (Required)
Bearer followed by token
Default: Bearer {{token}}
Body Request example Content-Type: application/json
TBD. It is necessary to get from the API developers versions of the code in all languages (Python, C, JS (Fetch, jQuery, Axios, XMLHttpRequest) etc.</description></item><item><title>How to create a pull request with git</title><link>/techdoc/git/pullrequest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/git/pullrequest/</guid><description>Find a repository where the owner made you a collaborator. You should get a letter with invitation to your mail. Create a fork of the original repository. Create a clone of this forked repository. For that: a) copy the address of that forked repository; b) open the folder where you are going to clone this repository; c) open the terminal inside this folder; d) write the command: git clone {the address of the forked repository}, for example: git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>Аліш’я Ніколь Гаррис: «Я передусім естрадний поет-перформер»</title><link>/articles/litakcent/harris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/litakcent/harris/</guid><description>Інтервʼю Ця поетка подорожує всім світом, отримує ступінь доктора лінгвістики Йєльського університету, а також належить до членів спільноти Phi Beta Kappa, її перформанси збирають мільйони переглядів на YouTube і вражають своїми оголеними емоціями та відвертими фразами. Цього року зірка поезії «spoken word» відвідала Львівський Форум видавців та завітала до Києва за сприяння посольства США в Україні.
Я прочитав ваш вірш «Південне» (Southern) та пригадав декількох великих письменниць, що належать до напряму «південної готики»: Фленері О’Коннор, Гарпер Лі, Карсон Маккалерс та ще багато інших.</description></item><item><title>How to place API in a table</title><link>/techdoc/api/api_in_the_table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/api/api_in_the_table/</guid><description>Create some boiler plates To present API data in a table online create three files in a folder:
index.html script.js style.css Then add bootstrap code to index.html to get the table fast. Open the Bootstrap service, click on the &amp;ldquo;Read the Docs&amp;rdquo; button and find CDN links paragraph on the page.
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;#34;en&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;#34;UTF-8&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;#34;X-UA-Compatible&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;IE=edge&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;#34;viewport&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;API data in table&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;stylesheet&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;https://cdn.</description></item><item><title>Люди в гніздах: токсична реакція на родинні саги</title><link>/articles/litakcent/kotsarev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/litakcent/kotsarev/</guid><description>Олег Коцарев. Люди в гніздах. К. : Комора, 2018 Українські літератори написали чимало родинних саг, і їх видання подекуди починає ставати схожим на конвеєр. Деякі напрацьовані прийоми та правила повторюються, а творчі знахідки зустрічаються дедалі рідше. Не дивно, що автори, схильні до критичного погляду на літературу та пародій, до яких належить і Олег Коцарев, убачають у цьому привід для кепкування. Тому новий його роман «Люди в гніздах» можна вважати літературним жартом, або й шаржем.</description></item><item><title>API terms</title><link>/techdoc/api/apiterms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/api/apiterms/</guid><description>Resource URL Copy https://api.openweathermap.org/surfreport/{beachId} Endpoint Copy /surfreport/{beachId}` Path parameter Path parameter should be represented in curly braces:
Copy {beachId} Parameters Parameters are options you can pass with the endpoint (such as specifying the response format or the amount returned) to influence the response. There are several types of parameters:
header parameters: are included in the request header, usually related to authorization. path parameters: are within the path of the endpoint, before the query string (?</description></item><item><title>Terraform Docs</title><link>/techdoc/javascript/readme_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/javascript/readme_1/</guid><description>Required Inputs No required inputs.
Optional Inputs The following input variables are optional (have default values):
aws_access_key Description: Precreated AWS access key.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
aws_ecr_region Description: AWS ECR region.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;us-west-2&amp;quot;
aws_region Description: AWS region.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;us-west-2&amp;quot;
aws_s3_backup_bucket Description: s3 backup backet name
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;se-tpm-develop-backup-bucket&amp;quot;
aws_secret_key Description: Precreated AWS secret key.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
backend_port Description: The port the service on the EKS instances listen on.</description></item><item><title>Том Генкс наклацав на друкарській машинці кілька історій</title><link>/articles/litakcent/tom-hanks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/litakcent/tom-hanks/</guid><description>Том Генкс. Історії, наклацані на друкарській машинці / пер. з англ. Н.Гайдучик. Львів : ВСЛ, 2018 Збірка оповідань Тома Генкса одразу привернула до себе увагу багатьох читачів: на сервісі Goodreads їй виставили аж 16517 оцінок і написали 3336 відгуків. Професійні рецензії вийшли і в центральних медіа світу, таких як The Independent та The Guardian. Нічого дивного, адже цей актор — мегазірка світового кіна, а фільми за його участі переглянули сотні мільйонів людей.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Docs</title><link>/techdoc/javascript/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/techdoc/javascript/readme/</guid><description>Required Inputs No required inputs.
Optional Inputs The following input variables are optional (have default values):
aws_access_key Description: Precreated AWS access key.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
aws_ecr_region Description: AWS ECR region.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;us-west-2&amp;quot;
aws_region Description: AWS region.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;us-west-2&amp;quot;
aws_s3_backup_bucket Description: s3 backup backet name
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;se-tpm-develop-backup-bucket&amp;quot;
aws_secret_key Description: Precreated AWS secret key.
Type: string
Default: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
backend_port Description: The port the service on the EKS instances listen on.</description></item><item><title>Ірина Цілик та південна готика</title><link>/articles/litakcent/tsilyk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/litakcent/tsilyk/</guid><description>Ірина Цілик. Родимки. — К. : Санченко: Електрокнига, 2012 Нова книжка Ірини Цілик «Родимки» несподівано змусила мене глянути на українську літературу ззовні. Звісно, малоймовірно було би припускати, що вона розвивається окремо від іншого світу — у нас мають бути аналоги загальновідомих авторів. Одразу підкреслю, що йдеться не про копіювання та епігонство, а лише про схожу «механіку» твору, що виникає внаслідок протистояння антагоністичних сутностей: саме так, на мою думку, і виникає література.</description></item><item><title/><link>/articles/bukvoid/kruger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/bukvoid/kruger/</guid><description>Чарівна Коробка Вано Крюгера Вано Крюгер. Прощальний поцілунок Ілліча. К.: Люта справа. 2015, -128 с. Вірші Вано Крюгера геть позбавлені сенсу. Якщо вам раптом почне здаватися, що він там є, то автор старанно кожним рядком переконає вас у зворотньому. Спостерігати за цією ретельною та послідовною семантичною анігіляцією цікаво, хоча сам процес призводить до безрадісних висновків.
Вірш “Медитація Тибетського лами” розповідає історію перетворення тибетського чернеця Лаврентія Берія на ламу після медитації, яка закінчується видінням розстрілу бранки, де процес страти уподібнюється до сексуального акту, а маузер - до статевого органу.</description></item><item><title/><link>/articles/bukvoid/vertygolov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/bukvoid/vertygolov/</guid><description>Вертиголов: наслідки зіткнення галактик Вертиголов та інші політичні тварини. Антологія німецької літератури 90-х років ХХст. К.: Грані-Т. 2011, - 294 с. Німецький астрофізик Раймар Люст спрогнозував наслідки зіткнення нашої галактики Чумацький Шлях із галактикою Туманність Андромеди (М31), яке відбудеться приблизно через п&amp;rsquo;ять мільярдів років.
За гіпотезою Люста те, що відбудеться, важко назвати справжнім зіткненням, бо мінімальна відстань поміж зірками становить декілька десятків мільйонів їх діаметрів. «Колесо М31 пройде крізь Чумацький Шлях немов примара, - каже Люст, - але ця зустріч, безперечно, буде мати серйозні наслідки для нас усіх».</description></item><item><title/><link>/articles/kyivdaily/new-daily-doc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/kyivdaily/new-daily-doc/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>